{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Palau","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Iran","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Ngerulmud is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jackie kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["Michelle Obama","Mary Todd Lincoln","Barbara Bush"],"question":"Who was the first First Lady to be received privately by the Pope? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Bahrain","Laos"],"question":"Moules-Frites is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Genesis","incorrectAnswers":["Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark","Soft Machine","The Human League"],"question":"Which band includes 'Peter Gabriel'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hermione Granger","incorrectAnswers":["Ron Weasley","Harry Potter","Luna Lovegood"],"question":"In the 'Harry Potter' series, which character has a ginger cat named Crookshanks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Swedish ","incorrectAnswers":["English","French","American"],"question":"What Nationality Was The Chemist Alfred Nobe?l","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neville Longbottom","incorrectAnswers":["Neville Fathead","Neville Roundnose","Neville Squatfoot"],"question":"Which of these is a character in Harry Potter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Ice Hockey","Cricket","Sailing"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Ryder Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Riga Black Balsam","incorrectAnswers":["Unicum","Sangria","Chapalo"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Latvia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Aluminium","incorrectAnswers":["Oxygen","Silicon","Iron"],"question":"Which element makes up 8.13% of the Earth's crust","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Squash","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Rugby","Tennis"],"question":"With Which Sport Would You Associate Jahangir Khan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["France","Ireland","Greece"],"question":"From what country does the protagonist of the book 'The Girl Who Kicked the Hornet's Nest' hail?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crop circles","incorrectAnswers":["Sex","Organic particles","Moons"],"question":"What is cereology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Canaries","incorrectAnswers":["The Tigers","The Foxes","The Posh"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Norwich City?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Book of Lost Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Brahma","incorrectAnswers":["Vishnu","Brihaspati","Krishna"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu god of creation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A mother personally challenges the local authorities to solve her daughter's murder.","incorrectAnswers":["The drug-induced utopias of four addicts are shattered when their addictions run deep.","A paleontologist is tasked with protecting two children when cloned dinosaurs are set free.","A destitute family builds a symbiotic relationship with a wealthy family."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United States of America","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","Belize","Guatemala"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Canada?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A rag","incorrectAnswers":["A nest","A watch","A stud"],"question":"What is the word for a group of colts?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Epictetus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Happiness lies in virtuous activity, and perfect happiness lies in the best activity, which is contemplative'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Verba volant, scripta manent","incorrectAnswers":["Dies irae","Incepto ne desistam","Barba non facit philosophum"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Words fly away, writings remain'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A litter","incorrectAnswers":["A flight","A barren","A bevy"],"question":"What is the word for a group of cubs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["Paul & Garfunkel","Mitch & Garfunkel","Art & Garfunkel"],"question":"Which band did Art Garfunkel belong to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Rhine ","incorrectAnswers":["The Seine","The Elbe","The Danube"],"question":"Which River Forms A Border Between France & Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aretha Franklin","incorrectAnswers":["Whitney Houston","Tina Turner","Diana Ross"],"question":"Who duetted with George Michael in the song 'I Knew You Were Waiting (For Me)'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dominican Republic","incorrectAnswers":["Haiti","Jamaica","Saint Kitts and Nevis"],"question":"What country is Santo Domingo the capital of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Uralic","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'Southern Pashto' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fermentation","incorrectAnswers":["Cartography","Substitution","Titration"],"question":"What process is used for making beer, wine and sourdough bread?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'As You Like It'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Left-handed","incorrectAnswers":["Lightweight","Quick-footed","Unpredictable"],"question":"In boxing, what is meant by, the term 'southpaw'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Bosnia & Herzegovina","France","Italy"],"question":"In which country would you find the ancient Greek city of Hierapolis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Everything's Eventual'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["London","Nanjing","Amsterdam"],"question":"Which City Did The Allies Liberate On August 25th 1944?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Wolves","incorrectAnswers":["Cottagers","The Cherries","The Boro"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Wolverhampton Wanderers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Sign of the Four'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Germany and the Soviet Union","incorrectAnswers":["Japan and the United States","Britain and France","Italy and France"],"question":"Which two countries signed the Non-Aggression Pact of 1939?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Green","Black"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Poland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gandhi","incorrectAnswers":["E.T. The Extra-Terrestrial","Missing","Tootsie"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1982?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'The Unforgettable Fire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["United States","Guatemala","Spain"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three vertical bands of green white and red with a symbol in the middle.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Joan of Arc","incorrectAnswers":["Mary Magdalene","St. Theresa","St. Catherine"],"question":"Which famous martyr is the heroine of many operas, including \"The Maid of Orleans\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Hot Child in the City","incorrectAnswers":["96 Tears","99 Luftballoons","I'm Gonna Be (500 Miles)"],"question":"Nick Gilder had a one hit wonder in 1978 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anthrax","incorrectAnswers":["Salmonella","Botulism","Staphylococcus"],"question":"What bacterial toxin was used in a number of attacks in late 2001?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American hard rock band released the song 'Sweet Child O' Mine'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Turkmenistan is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kojak","incorrectAnswers":["Shaft","Coffy","Black Belt Jones"],"question":"'Who loves ya, baby?' was the catchphrase of which 70s TV sleuth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The formation of vegetable mould, through the action of worms : with observations on their habits'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pleiades","incorrectAnswers":["Perseids","Nymphoids","Sorestas"],"question":"Which cluster of stars is also known as the Seven Sisters?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"plosive","incorrectAnswers":["nasal","approximant","fricative"],"question":"In phonetics, the b in 'boat' is an example of what kind of sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Grapefruit","incorrectAnswers":["Lemon","Orange","Lime"],"question":"What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Vincent van Gogh","incorrectAnswers":["Pablo Picasso","Salvador Dali","Claude Monet"],"question":"Which famous artist went unnoticed during his life, and commited suicide aged 37 in 1890?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neuromancer","incorrectAnswers":["Altered Carbon","We","The Handmaid's Tale"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'The sky above the port was the color of television, tuned to a dead channel.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","Deep Purple","The Rolling Stones"],"question":"Which band includes Brian May as its lead guitarist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malaysia","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Bangladesh","Lithuania"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent","incorrectAnswers":["\"All Star\" by Smash Mouth","\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears","\"I Write Sins Not Tragedies\" by Panic! at the Disco"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Go shawty, it's your birthday, we gon' party like it's yo birthday.\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gary Oldman","incorrectAnswers":["Timothée Chalamet","Daniel Day-Lewis","Daniel Kaluuya"],"question":"Who won the 2017 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Winston Churchill in Darkest Hour?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Nepal","Bangladesh","Bhutan"],"question":"In which country is Madras? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Son of the Dragon","incorrectAnswers":["Evil Eyes","Blood Hunger","Lord of the Tower"],"question":"What Does Dracula Mean?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Callisto","incorrectAnswers":["Io","Luna","Titan"],"question":"Which moon is our solar system's most cratered satellite?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Chad","Finland","Liberia"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Three equal horizontal bands of white, blue, and red'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Cameron","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Terminator?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sado","incorrectAnswers":["Saké","Sashimi","Shabu Shabu"],"question":"What is the name of the Japanese tea ceremony?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Denver Nuggets","incorrectAnswers":["Denver Knicks","Denver Kraken","Denver United"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Denver?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Les Misérables","incorrectAnswers":["The Boy in the Striped Pyjamas","Romance of the Three Kingdoms","The Count of Monte Cristo"],"question":"In which book does the character 'Gavroche' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Somalia","incorrectAnswers":["Burkina Faso","Lesotho","Solomon Islands"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.so' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Céline Dion","incorrectAnswers":["Mina","Nicki Minaj","Kylie Minogue"],"question":"Which Canadian singer released the song 'My Heart Will Go On'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Mysterious Mr Quin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Slovakia","incorrectAnswers":["Lithuania","Poland","Iceland"],"question":"Kosice is a city in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Maize","incorrectAnswers":["Rice","Wheat","Barley"],"question":"What type of food was the most important staple of the Aztec diet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Portugal","Russia"],"question":"In which country would you find Notre Dame Cathedral?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"33","incorrectAnswers":["24","12","8"],"question":"How many vertebrae is the average human born with?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Malcolm McDowell","incorrectAnswers":["Clint Eastwood","Arnold Schwarzenegger","James Stewart"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Alex DeLarge in A Clockwork Orange?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["The Kinks","Oasis","Nirvana"],"question":"Which band was Benny Andersson a member of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pierce Brosnan","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Moore","Sean Connery","Daniel Craig"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in GoldenEye?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Frances Hodgson Burnett","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Arthur Conan Doyle","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Little Lord Fauntleroy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard Nixon","incorrectAnswers":["Donald Trump","Ronald Reagan","George W Bush"],"question":"Which President of the USA infamously allowed the bugging of the Democratic Committee headquarters?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A goat","incorrectAnswers":["A goose","A broomstick","Rudolph"],"question":"When visiting Finland, Santa leaves his sleigh behind and rides on what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"The Sound of Silence\" by Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears","\"1,2 Step\" by Ciara and Missy Elliott"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Hello darkness, my old friend...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Come as You Are'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Arab Emirates","incorrectAnswers":["Bahrain","Egypt","Jordan"],"question":"In which country is the city of Abu Dhabi?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"16","incorrectAnswers":["12","10","14"],"question":"How many balls are on a pool table at the start of a game?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Shirley MacLaine","incorrectAnswers":["Katharine Hepburn","Bette Davis","Emma Thompson"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Aurora Greenway in Terms of Endearment?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1945","incorrectAnswers":["1941","1942","1943"],"question":"In which year did the first atomic bomb drop in Hiroshima, Japan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Church of Scientology","incorrectAnswers":["The Chuch of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints","The Jehovah's Witnesses","The Church of the Flying Spaghetti Monster"],"question":"Deriving its name from the Latin word meaning knowledge, which church was founded in 1954 in California?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ivan Turgenev","incorrectAnswers":["Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Sportsman's Sketches'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bees","incorrectAnswers":["Encryption","Mythical animals","Publishing"],"question":"What is Apiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jon Favreau","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hiddleston","Kurt Russell","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Happy Hogan in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"El Cid","incorrectAnswers":["King Arthur","Charlemagne","Genghis Khan"],"question":"Who captured Valencia in 1094 and ruled it until his death on July 10, 1099?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Chipotle","incorrectAnswers":["Taco Bell","Qdoba","Moe's Southwest Grill"],"question":"Which fast casual restaurant chain is named after a type of chili?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Agent Maria Hill","incorrectAnswers":["Natasha Romanoff","Gamora","Valkyrie"],"question":"Cobie Smulders plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Moscow","incorrectAnswers":["Belgrade","Budapest","Odessa"],"question":"Where is Gorky Park?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Achilles","incorrectAnswers":["Narcissus","Hercules","Jason"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who was the son of Peleus and Thetis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Preening","incorrectAnswers":["Sweening","Greening","Feening"],"question":"What is the term for the cleaning process that birds engage in?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"William I","incorrectAnswers":["Anne","Richard II","William II"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1066-1087?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frasier Crane","incorrectAnswers":["Jerry Seinfeld","Chandler Bing","Michael Bluth"],"question":"Which famous sitcom character is played by Kelsey Grammer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Equatorial Guinea","Spain","Austria"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Lasagna?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mons","incorrectAnswers":["Volcanus","Patera","Alpus"],"question":"What is the Latin word for 'mountain' that follows Olympus and Pavonis in the names of Martian volcanoes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1985","incorrectAnswers":["1979","1991","1997"],"question":"When was the Live Aid concert?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rocky","incorrectAnswers":["All the President's Men","Bound for Glory","Network"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1976?","difficulty":"medium"},